    While working on Clockwork Destiny, a year after the passing of Neil
Peart, I dug through my notes and correspondence and found a letter Neil had
sent me, dated June 5, 2010. He had just completed “The Garden” and said, “I’m
sure it’s the most beautiful song we’ve ever written.”

    He was right.

    “The Garden” is the final track on Clockwork Angels, the last studio album
Rush ever recorded. It was a perfect goodbye, and you can’t ask for more than
that.

    When I finally got myself ready to write this novel, “The Garden” formed
the thematic underpinning for this last great story of Owen Hardy and Marinda
Peake. It was balanced by another of my favorite Rush songs, “Headlong Flight”
—“All the journeys of that great adventure . . . it didn’t always feel that
way. I wish that I could live it all again.”

    Or, as Neil Peart himself said, “Adventures suck when you’re having them.”

    As I looked back on Owen Hardy’s life, it also brought to mind the thirty
years of friendship I had with Neil, that remarkable process when your idol
becomes your mentor, then becomes your friend.

    My first novel, Resurrection, Inc. (Signet Books, 1988), was[…]

Excerpt From
Clockwork Destiny
Kevin J. Anderson & Neil Peart
https://books.apple.com/us/book/clockwork-destiny/id1598351092
This material may be protected by copyright.
